Guide to the Woolsey Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Theodore Dwight Woolsey Writings, 1811-1889; Series II; 5.5 linear feet (14 boxes)
  - Sermons
    - Gal. 1:6, undated (Box 42, Folder 131)
    - Gal. 4:4-5, 1852 (Box 42, Folder 131)
    - Gal. 4:4-5 (I), 1861 (Box 42, Folder 131)
    - Gal. 4:4-5 (II), 1861 (Box 42, Folder 131)
    - Gal. 6:9, 1862 (Box 42, Folder 132)
    - I Thes. 1:5 Characteristics of the Early Church, 1862 (Box 42, Folder 132)
    - I Pet. 3:1, 1874 (Box 42, Folder 132)
    - Colossians 3:3, undated (Box 42, Folder 132a)
    - 2 Pet. 1:4 Escape from Worldly Corruption, 1857 (Box 42, Folder 133)
    - 2 Pet. 3:3-13 Geology and God's Moral System, 1854 (Box 42, Folder 133)
    - Titus 1:16, 2:6, undated (Box 42, Folder 133)
    - Heb. 12:2, 1859 (Box 42, Folder 134)
    - 1 Jn. 3:2, 1861 (Box 42, Folder 134)
    - Rev. 7:9, 1855 (Box 42, Folder 135)
    - Rev. 21:5 (Printed), 1875 (Box 42, Folder 135)
    - Rev. 22:14-15, 1858 (Box 42, Folder 135)
    - Divine and Human Natures of Christ, 1859 (Box 42, Folder 136)
    - Installation of Rev. Barker at Yale College, 1877 (Box 42, Folder 136)
    - "Self-Propagating Power of Sin", 1868 (Box 42, Folder 137)
    - Fragments and notes, undated (Box 42, Folder 138)
  - History - General
    - Bibliographical notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 139)
    - Civilization, Leading Elements in, 1865 (Box 43, Folder 140)
    - Civilization - Progress in the Human Race, undated (Box 43, Folder 141)
    - Destiny, Remarks on the Idea of, in History, undated (Box 43, Folder 142)
    - Ethnography of Caucasus, undated (Box 43, Folder 143)
    - Reflections on the Last 80 Years, undated (Box 43, Folder 144)
    - "Rome to the Time of the Emperors", undated (Box 43, Folder 145)
    - Rome, German Invasion, Feudal System, Mohammedanism, Science & Art, undated (Box 43, Folder 146)
    - Russia and Turkey, undated (Box 43, Folder 147)
    - Tyre and Phoenicia, 1842 (Box 43, Folder 148)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 43, Folder 149)
  - History--European
    - "Downfall of the Hohen Hotten Family of Emperors", undated (Box 43, Folder 150)
    - England, c.1560-1649, undated (Box 43, Folder 151)
    - Europe and England--17th Century, undated (Box 43, Folder 152)
    - Feudal System, Origin of, undated (Box 43, Folder 153)
    - French Constitutions, undated (Box 43, Folder 154)
    - Lines of European Sovereigns, undated (Box 43, Folder 155)
    - "Medieval History, Plan of Lectures on", undated (Box 43, Folder 156)
    - Norman Influence on European History, undated (Box 43, Folder 157)
    - Prussia
      - "Family of Prussian Kings", undated (Box 44, Folder 158)
      - Schleswig-Holstein, undated (Box 44, Folder 159)
      - General, undated (Box 44, Folder 160)
    - Revival of Letters in the Fourteenth and Fifteenth Centuries, 1865 (Box 44, Folder 161)
    - Slavery: Christianity's contribution toward its mitigation in Middle Ages, undated (Box 44, Folder 162)
    - 1304 to Reformation, undated (Box 44, Folder 163)
  - History - Greek
    - "Alexander the Great"… translated by J. Perkins from Syriac, reviewed, with extracts, by TDW, undated (Box 44, Folder 164)
    - "Areopagus", undated (Box 44, Folder 165)
    - Athenian government from the earliest times to democracy, undated (Box 44, Folder 166)
    - Athenian State after the Persian War; Political system of Athens, undated (Box 44, Folder 167)
    - Bactrian and Indian Kings of Greek Extraction, undated (Box 44, Folder 168)
    - Demades the Demagogue, Circa1886-1887 (Box 44, Folder 169)
    - Judicial System, undated (Box 44, Folder 170)
    - Origins and Tribal Structure, undated (Box 44, Folder 171)
    - "Slavery in Greece", undated (Box 44, Folder 172)
    - "Slavery in Greece and Thessaly", undated (Box 44, Folder 173)
  - History - Reformation
    - European situation at the time of the Reformation, undated (Box 44, Folder 174)
    - "House of Austria", undated (Box 44, Folder 175)
    - "Plan of Lectures on period during and after Reformation", undated (Box 44, Folder 176)
  - International Law
    - Agents of Intercourse--Ambassadors, Envoys, etc, 1874, undated (Box 45, Folder 177)
    - "Alabama Question", Circa1863 (Box 45, Folder 178)
    - "Annual Examination, Senior Class", 1871 (Box 45, Folder 179)
    - Arbitration--contemporary, historic (Lecture 10 and others), 1876, undated (Box 45, Folder 180)
    - "Association for the Reform and Codification of the Law of Nations", essay on, undated (Box 45, Folder 181)
    - Basis and Possibilities, undated (Box 45, Folder 182)
    - Blockade and Search (Lecture 12 and others), 1871, 1873 (Box 45, Folder 183)
    - "Christianity and the Universal Law of Nations", undated (Box 45, Folder 184)
    - Civil War (U.S.), 1873 (Box 45, Folder 185)
    - English History and International Law", undated (Box 45, Folder 186)
    - Extradition (MSS, Lecture plus. a printed essay), 1876, undated (Box 45, Folder 187)
    - Institut de Droit International, announcement of conference, 1874 (Box 45, Folder 188)
    - Interference of states not united by political system (Lecture 4), 1876 (Box 45, Folder 189)
    - Limits, deficiencies, improvements in international law (Lectures 1-3); Case of the Virginia (Lecture4) Conflicts of allegiance and civil status (Lecture 5), 1875 (Box 45, Folder 190)
    - Neutrality, 1873, undated (Box 45, Folder 191)
    - Sovereignty and Independence of States, 1871 (Box 45, Folder 192)
    - Territorial Rights and Jurisdiction, undated (Box 45, Folder 193)
    - United States Policy (Lectures 5-7), 1876 (Box 45, Folder 194)
    - War (Lectures 7,8, and others), 1874, undated (Box 45, Folder 195)
    - World Law Foundations to Blockade (Lecture 1-12, Fall Term), 1875 (Box 45, Folder 196)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 197)
  - International Law - Treaties
    - Introductory Lecture, undated (Box 45, Folder 198)
    - Geneva Convention, 1864, undated (Box 45, Folder 199)
    - Brussels, Conference of: Lucas, Ch., 1874 (Box 45, Folder 200)
      "Rapport Verbal … de la Conference de Bruxelles relative aux Lois et coutumes de la Guerre"
    - Nassau, rules concerning, 1873 (Box 45, Folder 201)
    - Paris, Peace of, 1855, 1857-1858 (Box 45, Folder 202)
    - Paris, Peace of-1763, and Peace of Hubertusburg-1763, 1763, undated (Box 45, Folder 203)
    - Utrecht, Treaties of - 1713, n.f. (Box 45, Folder 204)
    - Vienna, Congress of, 1874, undated (Box 46, Folder 205)
    - Vienna, Peace of (1815) and German history, undated (Box 46, Folder 206)
      Treaties of Vienna, 1864; Gastein, 1865; Prague, 1866
    - Vienna, Treaty of or Treaties of, 1814 (Box 46, Folder 207)
    - Washington, Treaty of (Lectures 8,9), 1874, undated (Box 46, Folder 208)
    - Washington, Treaty of, and Neutrality, undated (Box 46, Folder 209)
    - Westphalia, Peace of, undated (Box 46, Folder 210)
    - 1846, Treaty of, undated (Box 46, Folder 211)
  - International Law--Rights and State
    - Attributes of the State (Lecture 5), undated (Box 46, Folder 212)
    - Christian Political Duties, Circa1820-1830 (Box 46, Folder 213)
    - Communism and the State, undated (Box 46, Folder 214)
    - Constitution of Connecticut, on the revision of, Circa1876? (Box 46, Folder 215)
    - Freedmen in Politics, Letter to a Southern Gentleman, 1880 (Box 46, Folder 216)
    - Functions of the State, Relations to conscience (Lectures 2-6) (Box 46, Folder 217)
    - Particular rights--property, contract, family, personal (Lectures 2-4), undated (Box 46, Folder 218)
    - Political Economics, undated (Box 46, Folder 219)
    - Political Philosophy, History of, undated (Box 46, Folder 220)
    - Political Science, reviews of, 1877-1879, n.d (Box 46, Folder 221)
    - Political Theories Since Grotius (Lecture 7), undated (Box 46, Folder 222)
    - "Practical Politics", undated (Box 46, Folder 223)
    - Practical Politics--notes, undated (Box 46, Folder 224)
    - Revolution, civil duties according to Scripture (Lecture9), undated (Box 46, Folder 225)
    - Rights--Lectures 1,2 and "Review", undated (Box 46, Folder 226)
    - "Social Compact (Lecture 8)", undated (Box 46, Folder 227)
    - "Syllabus of Lectures on the Doctrine of Rights and the State", undated (Box 46, Folder 228)
    - Miscellaneous notes, fragmented lectures, Circa1871-1873 (Box 46, Folder 229)
- Theodore Salisbury Woolsey Writings, 1833-1922; Series III; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The WRITINGS OF THEODORE SALISBURY WOOLSEY are divided into two sub-sections: "General" and "International Law," and are arranged alphabetically by subject or title. The "General" section contains a variety of Theodore Salisbury Woolsey's writings, including travel stories, essays on early American furniture and silver, American painters, biographical essays (including one on Theodore Dwight Woolsey), as well as speeches and material pertaining to Yale.
  The second section, "International Law," contains writings on international disputes, border controversies, interoceanic canals, Cuba, peace conventions, the Monroe Doctrine, the Spanish-American War, a series of lectures on U.S. Diplomatic History, Yale course material, and book re-views. In addition, there is a series of articles written for Leslie's Weekly during the period of U.S. involvement in World War I and the Treaty of Versailles.
  - General
    - Account of Myself--Travels in Europe, 1873 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "California (Southern), Some Superficial Remarks, Circa1892, 1922 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - "Colonial Silver", 1909 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - "Color Blindness and Its Dangers", 1879 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - "Decadence of this Republic", undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Dunlap, William: notes on his paintings and copies of news items, 1833, 1835 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Dunlap, William: "Painter and Critic--or the American Varsari", 1914 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Early American Arts & Crafts, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - "Episode in Maine", undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - "Fredericksen (Charles)", undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - "Frontier Valley", undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Hudson Bay Company, History of, undated (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Joseph's Silver Cup (2 pages of a sermon), undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - "Motor Vehicles", undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - New Haven: City Hall Plans: letters to the editor, 1924, undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - New Haven: Reforms needed (news article), 1910 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - "Old Silver" (Harper's), 1896 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - "Poe, (Edgar Allan)", undated (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Political Developments in the US c.1905-1910 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - "Quick Water and Dead: Sketches of Forest Life in the Maine Woods", 1898 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - "Red Cross, Story of", 1900 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Sharples, Early American Painter, undated (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - "Trail of the Serpent", undated (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Valley of Gold--A Prospector's Story, undated (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Wayland, Francis, Biographical sketch (Brown Alumni Monthly), 1903 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Wilson, Woodrow: "A Scholar in Politics", 1919 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Woolsey, T. D.: Biographical Sketch of the Years 1827-1830, undated (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Yale Coliseum prospect, undated (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Yale: Eligibility in College Athletics: letter to the editor, 1902 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Yale Honorary Degree Descriptions, 1912, 1916-1917 (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Yale Law School Centennial Address, 1924 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Yale Law School Graduation Speech, "Success", undated (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - Yale Exclusiveness--comments on a Register editorial, 1899 (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - International Law
    - "Alaska Boundary Dispute", notes, including an article by Thomas Hodgins, The Alaska Boundary Tribunal and International Law, 1904 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - "Arbitration Once More: a Discordant note" State Bar Association of Connecticut, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Arbitration, notes for senior lecture, 1899 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Arbitration, Special vs. General, 1896 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Asylum, Limitations on, undated (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Balance of Power Principle and European Concert, 1903 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Belligerent Warships in Neutral Ports, 1905 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - "Bering Sea, or Sealing Controversy", including the printed convention of 1892, undated (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Canal
      - Attitudes of Maritime States, Circa 1886. (Box 48, Folder 43)
      - "Canal and the Monroe Doctrine", news editorial and letters, 1880 (Box 48, Folder 44)
      - "Interoceanic Canals", undated (Box 48, Folder 45)
      - "Interoceanic Canals as an International Question, undated (Box 48, Folder 46)
      - "Law No. 28 of 1878", convention for opening of a canal (Box 48, Folder 47)
      - "Suez and Panama; a Parallel", 1902 (Box 48, Folder 48)
      - "Suez Canal", 1887 (Box 48, Folder 49)
      - Yale Course, notes and queries, undated (Box 48, Folder 50)
    - Contraband, Rights of, 1914 (Box 48, Folder 51)
    - Convention for the Amelioration of the Condition of the Wounded in Armies in the Field, typescript copy, 1906 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    - "Convention for the Pacific Settlement of International Disputes" (Hague Convention), 1899 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Cuba (Box 48, Folder 53)
      - Cuba and Intervention, 1898 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - "Cuban Belligerency, Consequences of", undated (Box 48, Folder 55)
      - "Cuban Relations and the War with Spain", undated (Box 48, Folder 56)
    - "Fishery Question", undated (Box 48, Folder 57)
    - "German Victory?" printed, 1916 (Box 48, Folder 58)
    - "Government Debts Held Abroad", undated (Box 48, Folder 59)
    - International Law, student notebook, Univ. of Leipzig (probably not in Woolsey's hand), 1874-1875 (Box 48, Folder 59a)
    - League of Peace, minutes of discussions of the Century Association, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 60)
    - "Mexico and the French Intervention", 1896 (Box 48, Folder 61)
    - Mexico & U.S.--printed conventions concerning boundary rights, 1883, 1889-1890 1894-1897 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - Monroe Doctrine
      - Conformance to International Law, 1903-1904 (Box 48, Folder 63)
      - "Drago and the Drago Doctrine", 1921-1922 (Box 48, Folder 64)
      - "Monroe Doctrine", undated (Box 48, Folder 65)
      - "Monroe Doctrine Fundamentals", undated (Box 48, Folder 66)
      - "President's Monroe Doctrine", undated (Box 48, Folder 67)
    - Naturalization Question between North Germany and the U.S., undated (Box 48, Folder 68)
    - Neutral Trade and the War Zone, undated (Box 48, Folder 69)
    - Neutrality and Civil War, undated (Box 48, Folder 70)
    - Petition to the President, Comments on printed, 1916 (Box 48, Folder 71)
    - "Revolution, American, Diplomatic History of the", undated (Box 49, Folder 72)
    - "Rights and Duties of Americans When Outside the U.S. notes for a lecture, 1901 (Box 49, Folder 73)
    - "Russia, Expansion of", Circa1905 (Box 49, Folder 74)
    - "Spain, Our Duty to", 1897 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - Spanish War: U.S. Policy and Conduct, Circa1898 (Box 49, Folder 76)
    - U.S. Diplomatic History Lecture Series:
      - Neutrality of U.S. from 1793-1812 (Lectures 1-3), Circa1877 (Box 49, Folder 77)
      - Territorial Growth and Establishment of Boundaries (Lectures 4-6), 1877 (Box 49, Folder 78)
      - Civil War (Box 49, Folder 78)
        - Relations With Britain (Lecture 7), undated (Box 49, Folder 79)
        - Naval Power and Blockade (Lecture 8), 1877 (Box 49, Folder 80)
        - Alabama Claims (Lecture 9), 1877 (Box 49, Folder 81)
      - Treaty of Washington and the Geneva Arbitration (Lecture 10), 1877 (Box 49, Folder 82)
    - Venezuela Boundary Dispute with Britain, newsclipping, 1895 (Box 49, Folder 83)
    - Versailles: "America Stronger In Than Outside of the League" printed, 1919 (Box 49, Folder 84)
    - Warfare, Recent Changes in the Methods of, 1883 (Box 49, Folder 85)
    - Yale Courses
      - "Preliminary Lecture", undated (Box 49, Folder 86)
      - Synopsis of a course, Yale Law School, 1893 (Box 49, Folder 87)
      - Test and Exam Questions printed, 1903-1911 (Box 49, Folder 88)
    - Book Reviews
      - Balkan Wars: Report of the International Commission on (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 89)
      - Hauotaux, G., La Politique de 1'Equilibre, Circa1912 (Box 49, Folder 90)
      - Hogan, Albert E., Pacific Blockade, 1909 (Box 49, Folder 91)
      - Hyde, C.C., International Law, Chiefly as Interpreted… by the U.S., 1922 (Box 49, Folder 92)
      - Kraus, Herbert, Die Monroedoktrin …, Circa1913 (Box 49, Folder 93)
      - Powell, Major, "Lands of the Arid Regions of the U.S", 1886 (Box 49, Folder 94)
      - Wilson, George G., International Law, printed, 1923 (Box 49, Folder 95)
    - Leslie's Weekly articles and related newsclippings
      - "Has England Violated Our Rights?", 1915 January 28 (Box 50, Folder 96)
      - "'Lusitania' Tragedy, The Blame for", 1915 May 27 (Box 50, Folder 97)
      - "The Case for the Munitions Trade", 1915 July 29 (Box 50, Folder 98)
      - "Reply to Great Britain", 1915 November 25 (Box 50, Folder 99)
      - "Sanity in Preparedness", 1915 December 23 (Box 50, Folder 100)
      - "Dangers in Premature Peace", 1917 January 11 (Box 50, Folder 101)
      - "Peace Without Victory a Truce", 1917 February 15 (Box 50, Folder 102)
      - "Shall We Join the Entente?", 1917 May 17 (Box 50, Folder 103)
      - "Peace Terms: American and British", 1918 January 26 (Box 50, Folder 104)
      - "Russian Peace and Russian Pieces", 1918 March 9 (Box 50, Folder 105)
      - "Pay Day for Germany", 1918 November 30 (Box 50, Folder 106)
      - "Are the Senate's Hands Tied?", 1919 May 31 (Box 50, Folder 107)
- Printed Materials, Miscellaneous Writings, and Photographs, 1754-1936; Series IV; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series consists of articles, addresses, photos, and reports by or about various members of the Woolsey family. Much of the material, e.g., biographical sketches, academic documents, description of election and ordination, obituaries and eulogies, pertains to Theodore Dwight Woolsey. There are also reports and historical accounts of Yale. In addition, there is a section containing photographs of Theodore Dwight Woolsey and William Dunlap, their uncle, an early American painter, in whom both Theodore Dwight and Theodore Salisbury Woolsey took an interest, and Edward E. Salisbury.
  It should be noted that the materials in folders 42, 46, 48, and 50, while belonging with this series, are not printed matter. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
  - Art Works--catalogues, auctions, exhibits:
    - News items, 1899 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - William Dunlap, 1905, 1917 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Minatures, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - St. Memin, 1928 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Early American Portraits, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Catalogue of Flowering Plants … Around New Haven, "Sheffield Scientific School, 1878 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - The Club, New Haven, Connecticut, 1838-1886 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut, Historical Landmarks of, 1897 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, Jacob, Essay on TDW, 1899 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Dwight, Timothy, Funeral Address for TDW, 1889 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Dwight, Timothy, Inauguration Program, 1886 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Dwight, Timothy, Memorial Address for TDW, 1890 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - "Eaton, Daniel Cady", by William H. Brewer, 1895 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - "Edwards, Jonathan", by G.H. Humphrey, 1903 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - First Church of Christ, New Haven, Manuals, 1894-1895 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - French Protestant "(Huguenot) Church in the City of Char1eston, South Carolina", Circa 1898 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Harvard: Report Concerning Old South Meeting House, 1877 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Hazard, Mary P. B., memorial meeting, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Hazard Memorial dedication, 1920 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - "Herrick, Edward C.", biographical essay, 1862 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Hillhouse, Josephine: Will, 1897 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Home Missionary, vol. 78, 1900 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Home Missionary Society, editorial concerning, entitled "The Letter Against the Spirit", 1870 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Indians: Presidential Commission to Meet Sitting Bull, 1877 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - "Japan, on a Representative System of Government for", anon., C. 1890 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Matteson, Andre, "Proportional Representation in Illinois", 1872 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - "The British Invasion of New Haven" C.H. Townsend, 1879 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - New Haven Founders Day: 1638-1888 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - New Haven Colony Historical Society, 1901 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - New Testament and Psalms of TDW, undated (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Obituaries
    - Gilman, Professor David C., 1908 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Hillhouse, Mary Lucas, undated (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Sanderson, Baron, 1838 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Skinner, Aaron N., 1858 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - Pacific Service Magazine, 1922 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - Pemaquid, Report Concerning Ancient Remains, 1902 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Penitentiary System, Pennslyvania, Report on by French Inspector General, 1843 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - Porter, Noah
    - Biographical Sketch of TDW, Circa 1889 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - "Progress and Changes in Yale College in the Last Fifteen Years", 1881 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - "Reforms in Collegiate Education", New Englander, undated (Box 52, Folder 31)
  - Rome: Academic Course Listings, 1828-1829 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - "Sentimental Song Book", Julia A. Moore, 1877 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - "Smithsonian Library", 1854 (Box 52, Folder 34)
  - Sumner, Senator, Senate Resolution, 1872 (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Taft, Anna B., "Over the Hills and Far Away", memorial printing, 1916 (Box 52, Folder 36)
  - Universities: Bonn, Univ. of and Leipzig, Univ. of, regulations handbook (Latin and German), Circa 1818-1819 (Box 52, Folder 37)
  - Victoria, Queen: Wedding of, newsclipping, 1840 (Box 52, Folder 38)
  - "Wages, Profits, Rent, Value", anon., undated (Box 52, Folder 39)
  - Walker, G.L., Sermon on TDW, 1889 (Box 52, Folder 40)
  - Whig National Convention, newsclipping, 1844 (Box 52, Folder 41)
  - Woolsey, Rev. Benjamin (?), sermons preached in Connecticut towns (MSS), 1743-1754 (Box 52, Folder 42)
  - Woolsey, John Munro, July 4 Address, Petersham, Mass., 1929 (Box 52, Folder 43)
  - Woolsey, Melancthon T, Biographical Sketch of, 1899. (Box 52, Folder 44)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight
    - Fifty Years Service Medal Presentation, 1882 (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Minutes from Yale Corporation regarding election of Woolsey to Presidency & His Ordination, 1846 typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - Obituaries, newsclippings, 1889 (Box 52, Folder 47)
    - "Ordination of Theodore Dwight Woolsey", report by Pauline Pulcifer, typescript, 1919 (Box 52, Folder 48)
    - "Talk with Dr. Woolsey" a wide-ranging interview, New York Daily Tribune, 1881 (Box 52, Folder 49)
  - Woolsey, Mr. Theodore Dwight, Scripture Passage for the funeral of, typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 50)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, Academic and honorary degrees learned societies, 1842-1851 (Box 53, Folder 51)
    See also: box 51, folder 1
  - Yale
    - Alumni Weekly, 1905, 1912, 1915, 1918 (Box 53, Folder 52)
    - 1) Alumni Report, signed M.D. Collier, undated (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - 2) Commencement Day, 1846 (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - 3) Founding of Yale College, F.B. Dexter, 1882 (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - 4) "Yale College in 1885", Alumni Society (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - 5) "Yale College", W.I. Budington, 1871 (Box 53, Folder 53)